Suleyman Oner

Junior Mobile Developer

A highly determined and tenacious recent graduate of Information Technology with almost two years of experience working in various domains including finance and banking. Extensive mobile (IOS, Android & Hybrid) application development experience with strong knowledge of various programming languages including Java, Kotlin, and JavaScript. With a great passion for mobile software development, skills include analytical thinking and creative problem-solving, and wanting to be a part of a team developing cutting-edge mobile application and pursue an exemplary IT career in mobile development.



Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina

github.com/suleymanoner

+387644403683

in linkedin.com/in/suleymanoner

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Information Technology International Burch University

09/2017 - 07/2022

Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina

SKILLS



WORK EXPERIENCE

React Native Developer – Intern Finspire Technology

09/2021 - Present London, UK

Involved in a mobile application development team working on a banking application by utilizing React Native for creating both iOS and Android applications. Working in different phases of project life cycle like design, development, and testing of application for android and iOS mobile devices. Creating login, accounts, transactions, deposits, transfers and payments screen for a mobile banking app. Developing a mobile app for the company's primary service for visualizing data and reading industry news. Working in an Agile methodology environment and actively attending all scrum ceremonies. Implementing GIT and GitHub for version control. Attending in the weekly Java competition sessions within the team and always eager to learn from the other developers.

Android Developer – Intern Let's do it PL

03/2021 - 11/2021 Warsaw, Poland

Worked with other interns and developers on mobile applications by utilizing Java and Kotlin. Analyzed the requirements and designed a technical document for the requirement as a team. Developed the UI screens by integrating different views and windows to make them userfriendly. Worked closely with the web application development team to ensure proper integration between mobile application and web application. Also worked with other team members such as product owner, scrum master, and business analyst provided them my feedback in every stage of the development.

Software Developer – Intern Well Business Promotion

06/2019 - 09/2019

Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina

Involved in a software development team working on designing a website by utilizing Figma design tool. Focused mainly on UI development and had hands-on experience in designing attractive landing pages. Implemented web design and development principles to build stable software. Created mock-ups for better understanding of every process of designing a website. Experienced the scrum framework and learned new tips for creating preferable website designs on daily meetings.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Quotes (06/2022)

 Social media app was created with React-Native that users can share their favorite movie quotes.

Secure System Project (06/2022)

 Web app project was created with PHP, JS, CSS, HTML. It includes layered security challenges for website sign-up and login.

FoodOrderApp (02/2022)

 Food ordering app was created with React-Native that allows to users order food based on their location.

Letter to Yourself (06/2021)

 Web app was created with PHP, JS, CSS, HTML and it allows users to save their letters and choose the date that they want to send it.

Moviesfaction (05/2021)

 Movie searching app was created with Java, and it includes latest movies that allow to users find movies, watch trailers etc.

Countries (05/2021)

 App was created with Kotlin by utilizing RxJava, Coroutines, Retrofit, MVVM, DataBinding, and RoomDatabase and it shows some countries flags and details.

CERTIFICATES

Cybersecurity Essentials - Cisco (03/2022)

I learned how Cyber Essentials will help me protect my organisation against a range of cyber attacks.

INTERESTS

Mobile Development

Artificial Intelligence